A Guide to the Ford Foundation records, Arts and Humanities Program Files, Marcia T. Thompson FA1482
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Ford Foundation Stabilization Program, 1971-1993; 7
  - Ford Foundation Stabilization Grants III - Theater (3 folders), 1984-1988 (Box 51, Folder 418-419, Box 52, Folder 420)
    24. Negro Ensemble Company
    25. New Federal Theatre (NYC)
    26. Oregon Shakespeare Festival
    27. PAF Playhouse
    28. Playwrights Horizons (NYC)
    29. St. Louis, Repertory Theatre of
    30. St. Nicholas Theater Company
    31. Seattle Repertory Theatre
    32. Stage West (MA)
    33. Studio Arena Theatre (Buffalo)
    34. Trinity Square Repertory Company
- Education and Culture Program, 1956-1985; 8
  The Ford Foundation Education and Culture program was established in September 1981 to focus on five problem areas: the quality of teaching, the quality and content of scholarship, equity issues, cultural vitality and preservation, and policy analysis and dissemination.
  - Education and Culture Program - FY 84 Grants in the Arts and 1984 Budget Projections, 1980-1984 (Box 52, Folder 421)
  - Education and Culture Committee, 1982 March (Box 52, Folder 422)
    I. Education and Culture Preliminary Program Outline
    II. The Stabilization Strategy
    III. Cultural Preservation and Vitality The New Delhi Office
  - Education and Culture - Consultants and Terms, 1981-1983 (Box 55, Folder 459)
  - Education and Culture Committee: A Supplement to Part II - Results, 1982 March (Box 52, Folder 423)
    Mellon Symphony Orchestra Program: An Interim Report, 1972-1980
    Stabilization Program: Summary Status Report and Financial Highlights, August 31, 1981
  - Proposed Budget for Fiscal Years 1984-85, 1983 June (Box 52, Folder 424)
  - The Arts Program, Information Paper for the Trustees Committee on Education and Public Policy, 1980 March (Box 52, Folder 425)
  - The Education and Culture Program's Work in the Arts, Discussion Paper, For Discussion at the September 1985 Trustees' Meeting, 1985 October (Box 52, Folder 426)
  - The Education and Culture Program's Work in Higher Education: An Appraisal of the Issues and a Prospectus for Action, For Discussion at the December 1984 Trustees' Meeting, 1984 December (Box 52, Folder 427)
  - Ford Foundation Office of the Arts - Activities in Greece - Grants to Organizations, Travel and Study Awards, 1978 December 31 (Box 52, Folder 428)
  - Activities in the Creative and Performing Arts Visual Arts (1957-1980), 1980 September 30 (Box 52, Folder 429)
  - "All Our Ways and Means of Work --": A Discussion Paper Prepared for the Board of Trustees by Merrimon Cuninggim, Advisor, and "Summaries of Major Reports and Selected Memoranda by Merrimon Cuninggim and Mary Brucker" (2 copies), 1975 March (Box 52, Folder 430-431)
  - Education and Culture Committee, 1982 March (Box 52, Folder 432)
    II. Cultural Preservation and Vitality The New Delhi Office
  - Discussion Paper - The Stabilization Strategy: A Proposed Private Sector Initiative for the 1980's, Education and Culture Program (2 copies), 1982 December (Box 52, Folder 433-434)
  - Discussion Paper - Education and Culture: Excellence and Equity for the 1980s and Beyond, 1982 November (Box 53, Folder 435)
  - Education and Culture Committee - A Supplement to Part II - Results, 1982 March (Box 53, Folder 436)
  - Discussion Paper - The Stabilization Strategy: A Proposed Private Sector Initiative for the 1980's, Education and Culture Program, 1982 November (Box 53, Folder 437)
  - Education and Culture - FY 1982 Grants, Projects and Program-Related Investments Out of Appropriation and Delegated Authority Program (DAP), 1980-1982 (Box 53, Folder 438)
  - Education and Culture Records H8 (27) - Arts Program Activities - FY 83 Ending 9/30 - Modification and Summary, 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 439)
  - Education and Culture Records H8 (27) - Requests for Grant Action (RGAs) No. 676E - Support for Program Activities in the Arts FY 83, 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 440)
  - Education and Culture Records H8 (27) - Requests for Grant Action (RGAs) No. 6790 - Special $3.3 Million Arts Appropriations (2 folders), 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 441-442)
    Grantees:
    Small Grants Arts Delegated Authority Program (DAP)
    The Acting Company
    National Theatre of the Deaf
    Theatre Communications Group
    Yale University
    American Assembly
    National Arts Stabilization Fund
    Brooklyn Academy of Music
    School of American Ballet
    Joffrey, The Foundation for the
    Dance Theatre of Harlem
    The Art Museum Association
    Peabody Institute
    New York Public Library
  - Education and Culture Records H8 (27) - Delegated Authority Program (DAP) - 928-0204-150 - Small Grants Arts (2 folders), 1982-1983 (Box 53, Folder 443-444)
    La Mama
    Pedro Santaliz
    Women's Interart Center
    National Poetry Series
    California State University, Chico
    Elizabeth Swados
    Rhode Island School of Design
    City Center of Music and Drama
    Meet the Composer
    Clearinghouse for Arts Information
    National Opera Institute
    Davis and Elkins College
    Dance Perspectives
    Dance Notation Burea
    American Theatre Association
    Research Foundation of the State U. of NY
    Fund for Artists' Colonies
  - Education and Culture Program Budget, DAP Budget, RGAs, DAGs - FY 82 Summary and Modifications, 1981-1982 (Box 54, Folder 445)
  - Education and Culture Program Budget, DAP Budget, RGAs, DAGs - FY 82 Requests for Grant Action (RGAs) No. 676E - Support for Program Activities in the Arts (2 folders), 1981-1982 (Box 54, Folder 446-447)
    American Place Theatre, Inc.
    Artisans Cooperative (PRI Commitment Fees)
    Columbia University
    Alternate Roots, Inc.
    Kitani Foundation
    Arizona Theatre Company
    Connecticut Player/Long Wharf
    Hartford Stage
    Opera Festival/Lake George
    Opera Theatre of St. Louis
    Washington Drama (sp?) Society/Arena
    International Theatre Institute
    Mabou Mines
    Ballet Theatre Foundation
    Michigan Operat Theatre
    New York School for Circus Arts
    North Carolina School of the Arts Foundation
  - Education and Culture Program Budget, DAP Budget, RGAs, DAGs - FY 82 Requests for Grant Action (RGAs) No. 6790, 1982 (Box 54, Folder 448)
    Grantee:
    Shakespeare and Co.
  - Education and Culture Program Budget, DAP Budget, RGAs, DAGs - Delegated Authority Grants (DAG) 829-0204-150 - Support for Small Program Actions, 1981-1982 (Box 54, Folder 449)
    The Trustees of the University of Pennsylvania
    Kuumba Theatre, Inc.
    La Mama Experimental Theatre Club
    The Eakins Press Foundation
    Holy Names College
  - Education and Culture Program Budget, DAP Budget, RGAs, DAGs - Delegated Authority Grants (DAGs) 779-0820-350 - Program for Small Program Actions, 1981-1982 (Box 54, Folder 450)
    Eugene O'Neill Memorial Theater
    Leland Stanford Junior University
    San Francisco Redevelopment Regency
    Nation Institute
    Los Angeles Actors' Theatre Foundation
    Artists of Indian America
    Jerry L. Jaccard
    New York University
  - Ford Regular Budget - Grants and Out of Appropriation by Years, 1957-1981 (Box 54, Folder 451)
  - Ford Programs - School of American Ballet (SAB) Site Visits, 1973-1977 (Box 54, Folder 452)
    Folder is separated into testimonials/reports/correspondence of:
    Mrs. Janet Reed Erskine
    Mrs. Sonja Lindgren
    Mr. Robert Lindgren
    Mrs. Maria T. Paschen
    Mrs. Barbara Weisberger
  - Ford Programs - Administrative Interns, Catalogues, College Grants, Symphony Orchestra (2 folders), 1956-1985 (Box 54, Folder 453, Box 55, Folder 454)